Okay, so let's calculate the float then
using the one method and in fact the
calculation of float using the one method
is exactly the same as when we calculated
the float using the zero method exactly
the same.
It's basically late finish
minus early finish or
late start minus early
start or think logically.
B can start on day 3 or it could be
delayed by 3 days on start on day 6.
No impact on the schedule.
So B has a float of three, right?
So I'm basically using this formula.
It's 9 minus 6 or 6 minus 3.
The float is 3.
Same with C.
16 minus 13 or 10 minus 7, float is 3.
Right.
C can start on day 7 or it could start on
day 10.
It could be delayed by three days.
No impact on the schedule.
Same with F.
16 minus 15 or 11 minus 10.
F has a flow of 1.
And then G, 9 minus 8, 4 minus 3 has a
flow of 1.
And with A, D, E, H, and I, right,
they are on the critical path,
so they all have a flow of 0.
7 minus 7, float is 0.
9 minus 9, float is 0, and so and so far.
Again, same principle, right, is this is
total float.
B and C have a total float of 3.
B can be delayed by 3 days, or C can be
delayed by 3 days.
B and C in total can only be delayed by 3
days.
right so again if they ever ask you what
is a total float of a path total float of
a b c i is still going to be three you
never never add float values together if
float values are different you always take
the highest number total float of a b f i
right is still going to be three f has a
float of one b has a float of three you
take the highest total float
right so if they ever ask you what
is the total float of the path,
it's always whatever is the
highest of the total
floats of each activity.
Remember, a total float is how long that
activity can be delayed.
But remember, they share the float.
B and C will share this float.